# **Tobi Adeniyi**

Dartford, England • 7903 465 853 • AdeniyiSoftware@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/tobiloba-adeniyi-a5a306168/

# **QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE**

Enthusiastic and dedicated upcoming graduate with relevant education as well as ability to solve complex problems in a **Data Engineering** role.

- **Data Analysis:** Passionate about analysing big data using established statistical and machine learning techniques in order to deliver insights through charts and reports. Experience performing explanatory data analysis, using statistics.
- Programming Experience: Competed at Google's 2019 BGL hackathon to create solutions for victims of natural disasters.
- Data Science and Engineering: Skilled and experience in making analytic determinations through data science
  examination and evaluation of statistics, mathematics and computer science. Experience with Deep Learning,
  Reinforcement Learning, Geospatial Analysis, Natural Language Processing, and Time Series Analysis.
- **Key Strengths:** Strong problem-solving and analytical skills, as well as excellent interpersonal and communications skills, leveraging strengths in team leadership, cross-team collaboration, and project participation. Reliable to work independently, whilst thriving in collaborative culture.

#### Core Technologies:

Applications: MS Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint), LaTex

Tools: Python, SQL, Hadoop, JavaScript, R, MATLAB, Maple, HTML, CSS, Swift

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

Master of Mathematics - 2020 (expected 1st)

Loughborough University, Loughborough, England • Honours Graduate

SEO London Candidate - 2019

IBM Blockchain Foundation Developer - 2018

#### **EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

### Tutorful, Loughborough, England

#### Mathematics Tutor, 6/2018 - Present

Tutor math during after-school hours to children with learning challenges, including dyslexia and ADHD. Develop personalised lessons aligned with children's needs and learning levels.

- Mentored students that went on to achieve grades equal and above to that of peers.
- Encouraged five GCSE students to apply for STEM courses at university level.

# Loughborough University, Loughborough, England

## Treasurer, Boxing Team, 6/2019 - Present

Manage annual budget, allocating resources for all aspects of boxing events, including transportation and team uniforms. Maintain accounts receivables with membership fees.

 Slashed annual expenditures by £2,000 by creating excel spreadsheet comprising annual costs and streamlining overall accounting procedures for increased transparency.

### Graduate Student, Mathematics, 9/2015 - Present

Acquire knowledge of mathematical science, strengthening knowledge and applying research of mathematical modelling through analysis, mathematical methods, mechanics, computer applications in mathematics, statistics, and probability theory. Lead "Neutral Network" project, applying advanced regression technique and gradient boost regression aimed at achieving 85% accuracy on any give data set. Develop mathematical modelling skills and techniques to explore real world processes as well as mathematical formulation and models.

- Served as Vice Chair of the Athletics Society, supporting Chair on key decision-making and communicating mission to senior management as well as club and committee members.
- Chaired the Mathematics Department, overseeing all maths-related university activities and organising social gatherings with 86% student turnout.
- Held Ambassador position, guiding new students through orientation week, class enrolment and campus tours.